[{"id":1,"section":"basic","question":"What is Nodejs?","answer":["Server side js library","Nodejs is built on the Chrome's V8 Engine - hence very fast, many packages available.."]},{"id":2,"section":"mongodb","question":"How the mongodb works with node?","answer":["mongoose package to connect and manipulate the mongodb","a model is created using mongoose.Schema","this model is used to CRUD","model.find().exec().","","obj = new model()","obj.save()",""]},{"id":3,"section":"auth","question":"How authentication and authorisation is done?","answer":["Authentication:","a hashed password is saved in the db during sign up with bcrypt module","during signin the password is compared using bcrypt.compare","if success a JWT token is generated using email, id, expire time and returned to client","the client passes the token in its header on subsequent requests. ","an authentication middleware is used to verify the token, if succeeded the authorised route is processed further",""]},{"id":4,"section":"basic","question":"Multi thread app model and Single threaded model","answer":["#1. Multi thread model","    1. Each request is handled by each thread","    2. When the no. of req becomes high- the requests need to wait to get allocated to a thread [This can be solved my allocating more resources- which in turn is costly]","    3. The multi thread model causes blocks/ bottlenecks on the resources that they are accessing until they finished execution","    4. It works using thread pool","#2. Single thread model","    1. It works in an event driven way","    2. Each request is in the event queue, which will be processed asynchronously","    3. So there is no thread pool or block on the resource is not there",""]},{"id":5,"section":"basic","question":"Callback hell","answer":[" 1. To avoid callback hell, we can use named functions instead of anonymous callbacks","    2. This helps","        1. Easily readable code","        2. When exception/error happens the function can be identified easily through stacktrace","    2. Second method is modularize everything","    3.  use promise","    4. Use async and await"]},{"id":6,"section":"advanced","question":"Nodejs frameworks","answer":["Total.js","koa.js","express.js","socket-io.js"]},{"id":7,"section":"basic","question":"Node processes","answer":["","    1. Node js is single threaded application. ","    2. In order to get performance incriments it is possible to do multiple processes.","    3. There are 4 ways to create child processes in node","        fork","        exec","        execFile","        spawn"]},{"id":8,"section":"advanced","question":"What is babel?","answer":["Babel is a transpiler which converts es 6 code to browser compatible codes"]},{"id":9,"section":"urls","question":"Useful urls","answer":["1. Nodejs design pattern and much more - https://blog.risingstack.com/fundamental-node-js-design-patterns/","2. Nodejs best practices - ","        https://blog.risingstack.com/node-js-best-practices/","       https://blog.risingstack.com/node-js-best-practices-part-2/","3. nodejs style guide- https://github.com/RisingStack/node-style-guide","4. https://blog.risingstack.com/tag/node-js-tutorials-for-beginners/","5. https://github.com/RisingStack/risingstack-bootcamp"]},{"id":10,"section":"git","question":"Useful git repos","answer":["1. Rising stack - https://github.com/RisingStack","2. Max https://github.com/mschwarzmueller","3. Rising stack bootcamp course [complete nodejs]- https://github.com/RisingStack/risingstack-bootcamp"]},{"id":11,"section":"advanced,micro","question":"How to handle multiple routes with micro service?","answer":["What is micro service ?","http://blog.cloud66.com/scaling-your-nodejs-microservices-with-kubernetes/","https://github.com/zeit/micro/issues/16"]},{"id":12,"section":"advanced","question":"how multiple version of node is managed in same system?","answer":["Use nove version manager nvm package. brew install it.","","nvm install node verion will install a version","nvm use node version wll use that.","","This ned to be done as create-react-native-app require an older version than 8.9.4"]}]